Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory5 Mss.B.B61.inventory05
American Philosophical Society
Franz Boas Papers: Inventory (E-G)
1862-1942
Mss.B.B61.inventory05
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the Franz Boas Papers (Mss B B61). For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
Scope and Contents note
Due to the size of the collection, the content for Series I has been divided into multiple inventories. Please follow the links below to browse the inventories.
Inventories
Correspondents A
Correspondents B
Correspondents C
Correspondents D
Correspondents E-G
Correspondents H
Correspondents I-K
Correspondents L
Correspondents M
Correspondents N-Q
Correspondents R
Correspondents S
Correspondents T-V
Correspondents W-Z
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents E
  - E -- (illegible) (Box 24)
    - To Chavez, 1911 Jan. 13; 1p
  - Eames, Wilberforce (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1908 May 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1908 May 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1908 May 8; 2p
  - Earl, A.M. (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1905 Dec. 11
  - Earl, Mary (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1938 July 22; 2p
  - East Asiatic Committee (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1904 July 8; 5p
    - Treasurer's report, see W., I.H., 1905 Dec. 20
    - See FB, 1906 Jan. 2
  - Eastman, Mrs. Charles (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1942 Mar. 12; 1p
  - Eastman, M. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1934 Oct. 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1917 Dec. 21
    - To Boas, 1934 Oct. 19; 1p
  - Eaton, Edward A. (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1910 Jan. 7
    - To Boas, 1910 May 12
    - To Boas, 1920 Apr. 10; 1p
  - Eaton, G.F. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1925 Feb. 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1925 Feb. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 3; 3p
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 11; 2p
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 13; 1p
  - Ebding, E.F. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 5; 1p
  - Ebenstein, M. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1933 Nov. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 July 17; 1p
  - Ebert, L. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1936 Mar. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Mar. 16; 2p
    - To Boas, 1935 June 9; 2p
    - To Boas, 1935 June 29; 2p
    - To Boas, 1935 Sep. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Sep. 14; 2p
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 18; 1p
  - Eby, J.D. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1935 Jan. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Jan. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Jan. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 May 31; 1p
  - Eby, M.F. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1926 June 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1926 June 19; 2p
  - Eckert (Box 24)
    - see Tönnies, 1924 Apr. 31
    - To Lips, 1933 May 2; 1p
  - Eckhoff, H.E. (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1928 Nov. 26; 1p
  - Eckstein, Nathan (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 12; 1p
  - Economic Developments, Third Reich (Box 24)
    - 1936 Dec. 31, 12p
  - Edel, Mrs. Abraham (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1942 Mar. 12; 1p
  - Edel, Mrs. Bertha C. (Mrs. Leon) (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1936 Apr. 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Aug. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 July 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 July 6; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 July 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 July 9; 2p
    - From Boas, 1939 July 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 July 13; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 July 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 July 17; 2p
    - From Boas, 1941 Aug. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 31; 2p
    - To Boas, 1936 July 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Dec. 10; 2p
    - To Boas, 1938 Feb. 4 - 1939 July 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 July 10; 2p
    - To Boas, 1939 July 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 July 14; 2p
    - To Boas, 1939 Dec. 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Oct. 31; 2p
    - To Angulo, J. de, 1942 June 17
    - From Angulo, J. de (see margin of above), 1942 June 29
    - From Barbeau, C.M., 1940 Aug. 9
    - From Bloomfield, L. (see margin FB to LB, 1939 July 13
    - From Bloomfield, L. (see margin FB to LB, 1942 Jan. 8
    - From Bloomfield, L. (see margin FB to LB, 1943 Jan. 21
    - To Bloomfield, L. (see BCE to Cowan, J.M.), 1942 Dec. 30
    - To Bloomfield, L., 1943 Jan. 6; 1p
    - To Bloomfield, L., 1943 Jan. 20; 1p
    - To Bloomfield, L., 1943 Jan. 22; 1p
    - To Cowan, J.M., 1942 Dec. 30; 1p
    - From Cowan, J.M., 1943 Jan. 6
    - From Finkelstein, M.I., 1942 Oct. 25
    - From Hass, M.R., 1939 Dec. 13
    - To Hoijer, H. (see BCE Bloomifled), 1943 Jan. 6
    - From Kroeber, A.L., 1943 Jan. 5 & 28
    - To Kroeber, A.L., 1942 Dec. 30
    - To Kroeber, A.L., 1943 Jan. 6
    - From Newman, S.S., 1939 July 14
    - From Newman, S.S., 1939 Oct. 14
    - From Newman, S.S., 1939 Dec. 14
    - From Dearborn, N.H., 1940 Dec. 18
    - From Newman, S.S., 1940 Mar. 12
    - From Newman, S.S., 1940 Apr. 17
    - From Patterson, E.M., 1940 Dec. 18
    - From Salinger, 1942 Dec. 9
    - From Susman, A., 1940 Aug. 5
    - To Swadesh, M. (see Edel to Cowan), 1942 Dec. 30
    - To Swadesh, M. (see BCE to Bloomfield), 1943 Jan. 6
  - Edel, May (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1940 June 27; 1p
    - From Boas, 1940 Sep. 11; 1p
    - see FB open letter, 1941 Nov. 6
    - To Boas, 1938 July 22; 2p
  - Edenborn, William (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1905 Feb. 1; 1p
  - Edes, Robert T. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 8; 1p
  - Edge, W.E. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1921 Feb. 16; 1p
  - Edgerton, Franklin (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1923 Jan. 15; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Feb. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Feb. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Sep. 29; 2p
    - From Boas, 1941 Oct. 13; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Oct. 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 Jan. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 Jan. 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Feb. 1; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 21; 2p
    - To Boas, 1937 Apr. 18; 1p
      - enclosures, 1938 Jan. 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Sep. 26; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Oct. 13; 1p
  - Edmondson, T.W. (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1921 Feb. 17; 1p
  - Edmunds, C.C. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1917 Apr. 20
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 17
  - Edrehi, Isaac. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1933 June 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 May 30; 1p
  - Edwards, Charles L. (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1889 Aug. 10
    - To Boas, 1896 Apr. 14
  - Edwards, C.R. -- from FB, 1908 Apr. 15 (Box 24)
  - Eelts [?], Edwin (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1890 May 19; 1p
  - Efrón, D. (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 28; 2p
    - To Efrón, D., 1936 June 1; 1p
  - Efrón, David (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1934 July 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Aug. 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Oct. 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 July 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Oct. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Nov. 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Apr. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Dec. 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 Feb. 13; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 Mar. 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1940 Oct. 31; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Jan. 10
    - From Boas, 1942 Dec. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 12; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 June 26; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 26; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 July 11; 2p
    - To Boas, 1935 Apr. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 July 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 July 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 July 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Aug. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Apr. 20; 2p
    - To Boas, 1936 May 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 June 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 14; 4p
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 June 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 July 15; 3p
      - enclosures, 1937 Sep. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Sep. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Sep. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 29; 1p
      - enc., 1937 Nov. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec. 8; 1p
      - enc., 1938 July 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1938 July 24; 2p
    - To Boas, 1938 Aug. 7; 2p
      - enc., 1938 Nov. 3; 1p
      - see Soule, George, 1938 Dec. 11
    - To Boas, 1938 Dec. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 3; 2p
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 June 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 July 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 July 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 July 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Sep. 28; 1p
      - enc., 1939 Dec. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 July 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 July 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Sep. 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Oct. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Nov. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Mar. 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 June 2; 1p
    - To Allen, Jay, 1938 May 5; 4p
    - From Counts, Geo. S., 1938 Jan. 6
    - From Dunn, L.C., 1938 Jan. 17
    - From Efron, I., 1936 June 1
    - From Gruldi [?], Ennero, 1939 Mar. 27
    - From McAvoy, C.T., 1938 Jan. 31
    - From Rios, F. de los, 1937 Mar. 23
    - From Silver, H.M., 1941 Apr. 17
  - Egbert, James C. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1904 Dec. 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 19
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 3
    - From Boas, 1913 Nov. 15
    - From Boas, 1914 Mar. 6
    - From Boas, 1914 Nov. 14
    - From Boas, 1914 Dec. 11
    - From Boas, 1918 Apr. 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1919 May 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1919 Oct. 27; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1921 Feb. 28; 1p
    - From Boas, 1921 Mar. 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1921 Mar. 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1923 Jan. 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1923 Jan. 22; 1p
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1924 Nov. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1927 Nov. 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1927 Dec. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 28; 1p
    - From Boas, 1930 Jan. 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 Apr. 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 Dec. 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Oct. 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 Feb. 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1912 Oct. 14
    - To Boas, 1912 Nov. 16
    - To Boas, 1912 Dec. 2
    - To Boas, 1913 Jan. 16
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 27
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 3 or 5
    - To Boas, 1914 Dec. 12
    - To Boas, 1915 Mar. 10
    - To Boas, 1919 Feb. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1919 May 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1921 Feb. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1921 Mar. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1921 Mar. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1921 Mar. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 Jan. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 Jan. 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1924 Nov. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 Dec. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Jan. 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Apr. 20; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 18; 1p
    - see replies re Spain, 1938 Jan.
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 13; 1p
  - Eggan, Fred (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1941 Apr. 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 June 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Apr. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 June 16; 1p
  - Eggers, Carl (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1930 Oct. 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1930 Oct. 8; 1p
  - Eggers, H.C. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1930 Oct. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Sep. 27; 2p
  - Egli, J.J. -- to Boas, 1889 Jan. 20 (Box 24)
  - Ehrenreich, P. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 20
    - To Boas, 1899 Feb. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1899 June 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1899 June 27
    - To Boas, 1904 Nov. 18; 2p
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 20
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 19
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 19
    - To Boas, 1906 July 28; 2p
    - To Boas, 1906 Aug. 1
    - To Boas, 1906 Dec. 8
    - To Boas, 1906 Dec. 15
    - To Boas, 1907 Feb. 14
    - To Boas, 1907 Mar. 19
    - To Boas, 1907 June 26
    - To Boas, 1907 June 29
    - To Boas, 1907 July 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1910 July 4; 2p
    - To Seler-Sachs, C., 1924 Sep. 10; 2p
  - Ehrich, W. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1936 Feb. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Dec. 29; 2p
    - To Boas, 1936 Feb. 12; 1p
  - Ehrismann, Gustav (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1919 Dec. 25; 1p
  - Ehrmann, H.A. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1929 Jan. 28; 1p
    - From Boas, 1929 Jan. 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 Jan. 30; 2p
  - Ehrmann, H.R. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 31; 1p
  - Eichelberger, C.M. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1939 Apr. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Apr. 3; 1p
  - Eichenberg, Alfred (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Sep. 25; 2p
  - Eichhorn (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1927 Mar. 11; 1p
  - von Eickstedt, O.M. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1920 May 7; 2p
    - To Boas, 1920 Apr. 11; 2p
    - To Boas, 1920 July 5; 3p
    - To Boas, 1928 Feb. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 June 24; 1p
  - Einhorn, M. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1923 Apr. 17; 1p
    - From Schwalbe, J., 1923 Jan. 17; 4p.
  - Einstein, Albert (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1934 Jan. 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Feb. 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Apr. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Apr. 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Oct. 31; 2p
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 15; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 May 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Feb. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Apr. 10; 1p
      - see Catt, C.C., 1937 Feb. 10
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec. 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Apr. 23; 2p
    - To Boas, 1938 Aug. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Nov. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Feb. 19; 1p
      - to Aall, A., 1927 Feb. 19; 1p
      - to Marshall, Geo., 1941 Feb. 18; 1p
  - Einstein, Lewis (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1899 Mar. 14; 2p
  - Eisen, Miss Margarete (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 3; 1p
  - Eisenhart, L.P. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1942 Nov. 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Dec. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1943 Jan. 2
  - Eisenmenger, W.S. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 28; 1p
    - To Inst. of Interna. Ed., 1920 Apr. 24; 1p
  - Eisner, M. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1934 May 23; 1p
  - Ekern, Margaret (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 18; 2p
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 21
  - Ekerold, H. (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1924 Nov. 13; 1p
  - Eliasberg, Wladimir (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Nov. 7; 2p
    - To Boas, 1938 Nov. 15; 1p
  - Eliot, Charles W. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1901 May 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1905 Jan. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1916 Mar. 15; 4p
    - From Boas, 1920 Feb. 9; 2p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 1; 1p
  - Eliot, Martha M. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1941 July 31; 2p
    - To Boas, 1924 Dec. 18; 3p
    - To Boas, 1924 Aug. 5; 1p
  - Elizabeth (Box 24)
    Scope and Contents note
    see Dijour, Elizabeth
  - Elkin, Henry (Box 24)
    - see Boas, F. to N.Y.U., 1936 Feb. 25
  - Elkin, W.L. or W.T. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1909 May 27
    - To Boas, 1909 May 22
    - To Boas, 1909 May 26
  - Elkisch, Marianne (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1941 Jan. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Nov. 14; 2p
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec. 25; 2p
  - Ellery, Edward (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1929 May 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Dec. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Dec. 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Dec. 20; 1p
  - Ellinger, Esther Parker (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1918 Mar. 13; 1p
  - Ellinger, Leni (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 July 11; 2p
  - Elliot, I. or J.H. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1905 Sep. 19
    - To Boas, 1905 Sep. 12
  - Elliott, D.S. (Box 24)
    - From Roos, C.F., 1931 Oct. 31
  - Elliott, E.L. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1926 Jan. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1924 May 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 Jan. 6; 1p
  - Elliott, John Lovejoy (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1905 Sep. 20
    - From Boas, 1917 June 11; 2p
    - From Boas, 1917 July 30
    - From Boas, 1917 Aug. 9; 2p
    - From Boas, 1917 Nov. 14
    - From Boas, 1918 Dec. 20; 3p
    - From Boas, 1919 Jan. 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1919 Jan. 20; 2p
    - From Boas, 1919 Jan. 28; 2p
    - From Boas, 1919 Mar. 18; 1p
    - From Boas, 1919 Apr. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1919 Apr. 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1919 Apr. 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1919 May 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Mar. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Oct. 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Sep. 15; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Sep. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1905 Sep. 21
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1917 Aug. 1
    - To Boas, 1917 Dec. 21
    - To Boas, 1919 Jan. 13
    - To Boas, 1919 Jan. 22
    - To Boas, 1919 Mar. 28
    - To Boas, 1919 May 24
    - To Boas, 1935 Mar. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Sep. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Sep. 19; 1p
  - Elliott, K.A.C. (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 26; 1p
  - Ellis, D.C. (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 21; 1p
  - Ellis, George W. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1907 Aug. 9
    - To Boas, 1907 May 28
    - To Boas, 1907 Sep. 15
    - To Boas, 1907 Dec. 6
  - Ellison, E.S. (Box 24)
    - see Young, F.D., 1931 June 19
  - Ellwood, Charles A. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1931 Sep. 30; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 Oct. 5; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Feb. 4; 2p
    - From Boas, 1937 Feb. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Sep. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Feb. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Feb. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Sep. 29; 1p
  - Elsasser, F.M. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1933 May 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 May 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 18; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 June 1; 2p
  - Elsie (Box 24)
    see Parsons, Elsie Clews
  - Elsner, A.F. (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1885 July 17
    - To Boas, 1885 Dec. 5
    - To Boas, 1886 Jan. 18
  - Elsner, Kurt (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1905 Dec. 15; 1p
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1905 Nov. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 14; 1p
  - Ely (Box 24)
    - To Boas, 1907 April 2
  - Ely, M. (Box 24)
    - To Boas (open letter), 1918 Apr. 6; 1p
  - Ely, R.E. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 10
  - Embree, Edwin R. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 25; 1p
    - From Boas, 1930 Feb. 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1930 May 12; 2p
    - From Boas, 1933 May 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 5; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Dec. 27; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Mar. 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Feb. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Feb. 6; 2p
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr. 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Jan. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Mar. 26; 1p
  - Emeneau, Murray B. (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1942 Feb. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Feb. 10; 1p
  - Emergency Commit. in Aid of Displaced German Scholars (Box 24)
    - Assets & liabilities, 1934 Sep. 17; 4p
      - enc. with E.R.Morrow, 1934 Sep. 18
      - enc. with E.R.Morrow, 1934 Sep. 18
      - enc. with E.R.Morrow, 1934 Sep. 24
    - Report, 1938 Dec. 1; 13p
    - Minutes, 1934 Sep. 27; 1p
  - Emergency Rescue Committee (Box 24)
    - From Boas, 1940 Jan. 7; 1p
  - Emergency Society for German & Austrian Science & Art (Box 24)
    - Article, 1920 Dec.
    - Appropriations, 1920 Dec. 31; 1p
    - Meeting notes, 1921 Jan. 7; 1p
    - Minutes, 1923 Jan. 3; 6p
    - Meeting Notes, 1923 Jan. 26; 1p
    - Minutes, 1923 Jan. 26; 2p
    - Meeting notice from Heuser, F.W.J. per Robbins, J.C., 1923 Mar. 2; 3p
    - Order of business, 1923 Mar. 2; 1p
      see Schmidt-Ott, F.
    - To Börsenverein der deutschen Buchhöndler, 1922 Dec. 22; 1p
    - To Bewer, Julius
      - see Speyer, J., 1920 Dec. 31
    - To Busse, G.A.
      - see Speyer, J., 1920 Dec. 31
    - To Central Union Trust, 1920 Dec. 22; 1p
    - To Erbsloh, R.
      - see Speyer, J., 1920 Dec. 31; 1p
    - To Erbsloh, R.
      - see Speyer, J., 1920 Dec. 31; 1p
      - see Speyer, J. for same to:
        - Frank, K.G.
        - Kayser, C.F.
        - E. Baruch
        - H. Lieber
          see also below:
  - Emergency Society in Aid of European Science and Art (Box 24)
    see also above
    - Constitution & by-laws, 1920 Dec. 31; 6p
    - Minutes, special meeting, 1920 Nov. 30; 2p
    - Minutes, exec. committee, 1920 Nov. 12; 3p
      See Heuser, F.W.J.
      Wurlitzer, Howard
      Gundlacher, Ernest
      Lieber, Hugo
      Reinhold, Heinrich
    - To Keehn, Harriet, 1920 Nov. 1
    - To Keehn, Harriet, 1920 Nov. 27
  - Emerson, Ellen Russell (Box 25)
    - To Boas, 1889 Dec. 30
  - Emerson, J.T. (Mrs. Kendall) (Box 25)
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 25
  - Emerson, Mrs. Jos. (Box 25)
    - To Beckwith, M.W., 1926 May 5; 1p
    - with Beckwith, M.W., 1926 May 23
  - Emery, H.C. (Box 25)
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 1
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 7
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 13
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 15
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 26
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 27
    - From Boas, 1906 Apr. 6
    - From Boas, 1906 May 11
    - From Boas, 1906 May 23
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 30
    - From Boas, 1908 Mar. 31
    - From Boas, 1908 Apr. 15
    - From Boas, 1908 May 4
    - From Boas, 1908 May 12
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 5
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 12
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 13
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 16
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 26
    - To Boas, 1906 Apr. 3
    - To Boas, 1906 Apr. 7
    - To Boas, 1906 Apr. 8
    - To Boas, 1906 Apr. 9
    - To Boas, 1906 May 8
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 21
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 7
    - To Boas, 1908 May 12, 21, and 28
  - Emmerich. (Box 25)
    - From Boas, 1937 Feb. 18
  - Emmons, G.S. (Box 25)
    - To Boas, 1888 Dec. 15; 4p
  - Emmons, G.T. (Box 25)
    - From Boas, 1905 June 5
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 17
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 4
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 6
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 30
    - From Boas, 1907 Nov. 11
    - From Boas, 1908 Jan. 8; 3p
    - To Boas, 1905 Jan. 25; 2p
    - To Boas, 1905 Mar. 2
    - To Boas, 1905 Apr. 4
    - To Boas, 1905 Apr. 18
    - To Boas, 1905 Apr. 28
    - To Boas, 1905 Sep. 25
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 1
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 4
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 11
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 13
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 27
    - To Boas, 1908 Jan. 7
    - To Boas, 1908 Jan. 7
    - To Boas, 1908 Jan. 11
  - Emmons, S.F. (Box 25)
    - From Boas, 1911 Mar. 2; 2p
    - To Boas, 1911 Mar. 4
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 15
  - Emptage, Arthur (Box 25)
    - To Boas, 1938 Dec. 16; 1p
  - Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences (Box 25)
    - see Johnson, Alvin, 1928 Oct. 2
    - Pres.'s Report, 1930 Dec. 10
      - enc. with Seligman, E., 1930 Dec. 15
    - see Johnson, A.:, 1930 July 11
    - see Johnson, 1931 Nov. 20
    - see Johnson, 1932 Mar. 30
    - see Johnson, 1932 Apr. 4
    - see Johnson, 1932 Apr. 7
    - see Johnson, 1932 Nov. 22
    - see Johnson, 1932 Dec. 1
    - see Johnson, 1932 Dec. 7
    - see Johnson, 1933 Mar. 15
  - Endell, Fritz (Box 25)
    - From Boas, 1919 July 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1919 June 9; 2p
  - Enderlin, M. (Box 25)
    - From Boas, 1933 Mar. 28; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 May 25; 2p
    - From Boas, 1933 July 31; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 May 4; 3p
    - To Boas, 1933 July 1; 2p
    - To Boas, 1933 Aug. 5; 1p
  - Engelhardt, George (Box 25)
    - From Boas, 1927 Sep. 28; 1p
    - From Johannsen, O.A. to GE, 1927 Sep. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 Sep. 27; 1p
  - Engelhardt, N.L. (Box 25)
    - From Boas, 1918 Mar. 18; 1p
    - From Boas, 1918 Apr. 10; 1p
  - Engemann, Hedwig (Box 25)
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 Feb. 15; 2p
  - Engen (Box 25)
    - From Boas, 1913 Aug. 30
  - Engerrand, Jorge C. (or George C.) (Box 25)
    - From Boas, 1911 Mar. 28
    - From Boas, 1912 Aug. 23
    - From Boas, 1912 Oct. 4
    - From Boas, 1912 Oct. 14
    - From Boas, 1912 Oct. 23; 5p
    - From Boas, 1912 Oct. 29; 3p
    - From Boas, 1912 Oct. 29; 16p
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 7; 3p
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 18; 2p
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 22
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 25; 4p
    - From Boas, 1912 Nov. 27; 2p
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 5
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 10; 2p
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 12
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 14
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 10; 6p
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 16
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 17
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 3
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 4
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 8; 2p
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 10
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 17; 2p
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 17; 2p
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 18
      - notes for Gamio, 1913 Jan.?; 5p
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 23